Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Pacific Improvement Company Records,
1901-1966
JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
78.0 Linear feet
Pacific Improvement Company.
Scope and Content
Contains business records of the Pacific Improvement Company and its subsidiaries. Includes business and legal documents, correspondence, reports, minutes, deeds, annual reports, maps, and blurprints. Contains materials related to the Monterey Peninsula and its development. Business areas covered include land development, coal and iron mining, railroads, and hotels.
Historical Note
Pacific Improvement Company was a large holding company in California, formed by C. P. Huntington, Leland Stanford, Mark Hopkins, and Charles Crocker. The Company played a role in the development of land and railroads in various parts of the United States, but particularly in California and Texas. The Company was incorporated November 4, 1878 and completed liquidation of its assets in 1967.
Provenance
Gift of Crocker Estate to Jackson Library in 1970. Transferred to Department of Special Collections in 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
- P.I. Co. Miscellaneous
  - “Co(mpany) History - written by S.F.B. Morse, 1966 - four pages”. eulogy of Social Darwinism., 11/3/1966 - (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - “Corporation Papers”. Includes certificate of incorporation from Dept. of State, California, other certificates and resolutions, dated Nov. 4, 1878, 1907 - 1918. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - “Reductions of Capital Stock - Documents ”., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - “Reincorporation- ”. Includes Articles of Incorporation, two indentures, correspondence., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Reduction of Capital Stock- ”., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - “Dissolution - 1966”. Certificate of Dissolution for both P.I. Co. and C.H.C.C. filed endorsed by State of Calif. File contains original and copies of certificate for P.I. Co., necessary prime and reports completed by Accountant - John Forbes Inc. and lawyers - Orrick, Dahlquist, Herrington & Sutcliffe., 12/9/66 - 12/13/66. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - “Stockholder Lists - P.I. Co. and Affiliates ”., 1920-21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - “Stock Transfers”., Dated 1929-1936. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - “Liquidating Dividends”., Dated 1901-1968. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - “Texas & New Orleans R.R. (Railroad) Bonds (liquidating dividend- ”, 1941). (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - “Dividends Paid to Stanford”. receipts signed for Jane Stanford by Charles G. Lathrop, her attorney in fact., Sept.-Dec. 1901 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - “Dividends Paid to Hubbard & Co., Huntington, Huntington Estate”. Receipts and acknowledgements of receipts S.A. Van Devcer signs for P.I. Co., Sept. - Dec. 1901. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - “Crocker Estate Co., Origins, Dividends Rec'd”. Receipts signed by George Crocker for Crocker Estate Co., correspondence List made by Crocker Estate of Dividends received. Handwritten history of Crocker Estate, will and testament, Sept. - Dec. 1901. (3/7/16) dated 11/8/50. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - “Director's meetings - Notices, scheduling”. Includes miscellaneous correspondence with directors as well, Dates: Sept. 1933 - Dec. 1966. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - “Directors”. Includes a handwritten list of the original directors and officers and their dates and places of death; correspondence and form letters to directors. List of officers and directors of P.I. Co. at time of dissolution., Dates 8/17/15 - 12/27/66. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - “Director's Meetings - Notes of Meeting, Minutes”. One copy of minutes then begins 1936 through 1966., dated 9/12/01 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - “Miscellaneous Resolutions, Minute Excerpts”. Carbon copies, dated 5/1/02 to 5/8/31. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - “Financial Statements, Summaries and memoranda”. Includes year end balance sheets, dated 4/26/13 to 1967. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - “General Ledger Balance Sheets, 1892-1905. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - “John Forbes & Co. - Audit Reports ”, 1949-1959. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - “John Forbes & Co. Audit Reports ”., 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - “Bearwald & Rens - Accountants, Correspondence ”., 1944-48 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - “John Forbes & Co. - Accountants, Correspondence ”, 1949-67. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - “Miscellaneous Notes Receivable ”., 1879-1915 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - “List of Securities, Receipts, E.C. Wright, Treasurer ”., 1900-03 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - “Miscellaneous Notes Regarding Stock Certificates and Lists”., Dates 1890-1900. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - “Short Term Investments, Gov't. Securities ”., 1934-66 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - “S.F.B. Morse Commission”. Annual Accounting of S.F.B.M.'s 5% commission on all collections., (1945-1956) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - “Insurance”. Book recording all insurance transactions made by P.I. Co.'s Properties Feb. 1907 through 1910. Also misc. notes and correspondence re: P.I. Co. insurance and copies of 2 Insurance Contracts., Dates 1908-1930. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - “New York Office”. Includes testimony of Frank Davis, New York Agent and astorney of P.I. Co., in the matter of taxation of the P.I. Co. before Commissioner Walter B. Atterbury Testimony of S.A. Van der Veer, Asst. Secretary of P.I. Co. in N.Y., before Frank Sperry, Corporation Tax Commissioner attached to N.Y. State Comptoller's Office, Lists of Assets and explanation of financial situation for tax pruposes. Correspondence predominantly between Van Der Veer and P.I. Co. General Manager, A.D. Chepard, dates 1907 through D, 10/8/01. 2/7/06. c. 1934. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - “New York Office, Bank Book - Bank of America, Transactions closing N.Y. Accounts”., (1918-1919). (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - “Leases - P.I. Co. Offices in Santa Barbara and Seattle”. Leases made by P.I. Co., Santa Barbara - Seattle - Includes map of Port of Seattle., 1909, 1915. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - “Henry Cowell/Monterey and Salinas R.R., Loan Agreement 1875, C.P. Huntington Letter ”., 9/24/79 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - “J.H. Strobridge/D.W. Parkhurst, Investment Agreement, ”., 10/2/85 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - “Notes of Senator Wm. M. Stawart to P.I. Co. (one for $30,000, 1887 endorsed by Leland Stanford)”. Notes drawn up Correspondence between P.I. Co. officers re: notes, 1887 and 1891. Jan.-Feb. 1902. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - “Transfer of Lands Held by `Big Four' in Name of Crocker to P.I. Co. ”., 1888-89 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - “C.F. Crocker Loan to P.I. Co. 7/14/93, C.P. Huntington, Loan to P.I. Co. 7/13/93”. Loans paid back by the end of the month, and collateral, California Pacific R.R. Co. stock, returned., (July, 1893) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - “D.M. Seaton - Receipts for Payments of Legal Fees, ”., 7/21/93, 7/26/93, 10/3/93 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - “Jane L. Stanford Agreement dated ”., 12/5/98 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - “Statement of Operations, P.I. Co. & Affiliates - 1914”. Revenue and expenses broken down by each company still held by P.I. Co. in (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - “Salaries and Overhead, P.I. Co. Affiliates, ”., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - “Supplemental Agreement United Fuel Co.- ”., 3/10/25 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - “Sample Stationery, Checks, Land Dept. Forms”. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “Sample Receipt Books ”., 1916-1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - “Vouchers, Checks, 1930-55. (Samples).”, 1929-55. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “Journal Vouchers ”., 1929-30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - “Journal Vouchers ”., 1929-42 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - “Correspondence - Distribution of Checks, Routine Office Correspondence”. All correspondence to or from Jack Beaumont, Asst. Secretary P.I. Co., dated Feb. 1929 - Dec. 1939. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “General Correspondence”. Unimportant topics, dates 2/7/08 - 12/16/66. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - “Index to Correspondence, General Letters ”., April, 1906 to August 31, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Arrangement note
    Alphabetically by name of company or person. Under each name - chronologically.
  - “Bank Statements: ”., Jan. 1927 to May 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - “Bank Statements”., 1947, 1950-1954. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - “Bank Statements ”., 1955-59 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - “Bank Statements ”., 1960-64 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - “Bank Statements ”., 1965-68 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - “Bank Deposit Books Crocker Bank, S.F.”., 1913-67 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “Railway Express Receipt Books Significance Unknown”., 1938-41 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - “Miscellaneous”. Memos; notes; books and paper used for computing payrolls etc.; cancelled checks, etc. All quite old - before, 1910. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- P.I. Co. Legal
  - “Weidenfeld v. P.I. Co. 1920 - 1929”. Two actions one brought before 1920 another brought Weidenfeld i.e. trying to recover $709,953.78 (with interest has accrued to $2 million plus) from the P.I. Co. - specifically the Big Four - all dead. File contains predominantly correspondence between S.F.B. Morse and Adelbert Moot of Moot, Sprague, Brownell, and Marcy, attorneys in Buffalo, N.Y. Case is tried in New York State Supreme Court. Verdict in both suits in favor of P.I. Co., Weidenfeld awarded nothing. Court minutes of both cases, and history of case written as a letter by a letter to a John Hubbard Weidenfeld's attorney appeals to U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals., Oct., 1922. 12/13/28. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Weidenfeld v. P.I. Co. 1930-1939”. Welles V. Moot (Aldebert's son) now handling case. Again predominantly correspondence between Morse and the younger Moot keeping the P.I. Co. people up to date on the N.Y. proceedings. U.S. Court of Appeals affirms previous judgement in P.I. Co. favor again - copy of opinion included. Weidenfeld makes motion for reargument denied Further appeals and court opinions - correspondence and finally general release executed by Weidenfeld, July, 1930 - 1/21/1930. 3/21/1929. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Weidenfeld v. P.I. Co. - Transcript”. Transcript of Record in U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals - reviews entire history of case pre through, 1890 1929. Dated 10/16/1929. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Weidenfeld v. P.I. Co. Brief”. Brief for Defendant-in-error by U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals Review invalid, 1890 - 1928 12/28/28. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - “Central N.Y. & W.R.R. 5s '43 - Sample Bond”. Central New York and Western Railroad Co. Fifty Year Gold Bond Issued in redeemable in for $1000., 1892, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - “Central N.Y. & Western Bonds (Pittsburgh, Shawmut, & N. R.R.) - 1929”. Adelbert Moot's letters to Morse and copies of his correspondence to others in his attempt to collect money due P.I. Co. from Pittsburgh, Shawmut and Northern R.R. Explanation of history of case in letter from More to Herbert Fleishhacker, 12/31/29. Dates 9/22/19 - 12/31/29. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - “Central N.Y. & W.R.R. (Pittsburgh, Shawmut & N.R.R.) 1930-1939”. Same as 3-6 but Welles V. Moot takes over correspondence for deceased father, Adelbert. P.I. Co. takes over and reorganizes P., S. & N.R.R. in Copies of reorganization plans and agreements. Map of P.S. & N. line etc., (1929) 1932. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - “Central N.Y. & Western Rwy. (Pittsburgh, Shawmut & Northern) 1940-52”. Correspondence Morse and W.V. Moot. Monthly “Summary of Operations” and “Income Statement” from P.,S. & N.R.R., until they file bankruptcy in P.I. Co. collects their Central N.Y. & W. bonds which are worthless., 1946. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - “Weaver v. P.I. Co. (C.N.Y. & W.R.R.), Smith v. P.I. Co.”. Three booklets: undated opinions of Judge Woodward of Supreme Court of Allegany County in both case - in favor of P.I. Co., 3. brief prepared by Moot for P.I. Co. in response to State of N.Y. Supreme Court Appellate Division. Same two cases., 1 & 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - “Misc. Notes on Points of Law, Origin & Date Unknown”. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - “Van Fleet Correspondence ”. Routine, a few letters re: death of P.I. Co. counsel Earl H. Pier - formerly partner with Boalt., 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - “Van Fleet (House Counsel) Gen'l. correspondence- ”. Also includes copies of summonses and exhibits used in various cases concerning P.I. Co., 1921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - “Van Fleet Correspondence ”. Summonses and disclaimers re: P.I. Co. cases, included., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - “Van Fleet - General Correspondence ”. Affadavits, summonses, other legal documents for P.I. Co. cases., 1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - “P.I. Co. v. Pillsbury - 1920”. Mr. Pillsbury borrows $400 from P.I. Co. at 6% interest. Delays payment until Van Fleet initiates legal proceedings for P.I. Co. Amicable settlement is reached and debt paid by, 1920 - August 31, 1920. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - “Calif. Associate Raisin Co. v. P.I. Co. ”. Raisin Co. claims that P.I. Co. is liable for back taxes on land that they have since passed on to former concern. P.I. Co. objects court proceedings begin, but P.I. Co. ultimately pays without concluding the case., 1920 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - “Legal - P.I. Co. v. Alta Livestock (1920), (See Also: P.I. Co. v. Pacific Hog Co., ”. Again - failure to make good on note of debt to P.I. Co., 3-18) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - “Legal - P.I. Co. v. Pacific Hog Co. (1921), (See Also: P.I. Co. v. Alta Livestock ”., 3-17) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - “Legal - Mason v. Larkin - 1921, Quiet Title Action, Shasta City”., 5/29/20 - 12/21. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - “P.I. Co. v. Alexander (Suit for Collection, El Verano)”. Clifford Alexander., 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - “Legal-California Hotel Co. v. Joy Ryer Townsite Title”. P.I. Co. is a co-defendent with Mrs. Edna Ida Joy., (1922) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - “City of Los Angeles v. Southern Pacific R.R. et al ”. Dispute over land., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - “Legal - U.S. v. Certain Parcels of Land in the County of San Luis Obispo- ”., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - “Wilkens v. Herget (Mitchell's Cafe) 1914-16, Documents”. Background material dates to Wilkens attempts to foreclose mortgage on Herget's Cafe because of Herget's failure to pay debt. Includes booklet of Mitchell's Cafe Inc. Stock certificats., 1906. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - “Wilkens v. Herget (Mitchell's Cafe) 1914-16, Correspondence”. Stamp and cancellation Correspondence of Earl H. Pier, P.I. Co. counsel and partner of Boalt. Herget's notes., 6/3/14. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - “Wilkens v. Herget (Mitchell's Cafe) - Bills and Receipts”., 1914-1916 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - “Martin v. El Dorado and Placer Counties Gold Mining & Power Co., ”. Brochure for Company. Ned J. Martin was prospecting area and charges that company jumped his claims. Both Pier and Van Fleet serve as attorneys for Martin., 1916 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- P.I. Co. Legal, Taxes, Louisiana
  - “Clark v. Qucal, 1917 (Pier)”. F.W. Clark charges Queal with character defamation which is prohibiting him from obtaining a new cashier job after he left Queal's employ at McCloud Nat'l. Bank. Pier is Clark's attorney. Background dates from, 1912. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Legal - Furlong v. White (P.I. Co. not Involved, Van Fleet's case)., (1918) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - “U.S. v. Curtis, Collins Holbrook Co., Complainant's Briefs - Aid, Hudson & Benner and Kindred C ses”. three briefs. Case to do with money loaning and buying land., 1912 - (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - “U.S. v. Curtis, Collins & Holbrook Co., Complainant's Briefs - Mitchell, Johnson, Allen, Cooksey & Kindred Cases”. Three briefs. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - “U.S. v. Curtis, Collins & Holbrook Co., Abstracts of Testimony (Tuman, B.C.)”. Abstract (A) of Testimony of George E. Tuman; Abstract (B) of Testimony of: T.D. Collins, E.S. Collins, J.G. Curtis, D.G. Curtis; C.H. Holbrook, Jr., Arthur W. Elam, John H. Heppe, J.E. Remick, Charles E. Gregory; Abstract (C) of Testimony of: Charles A. Shurtaleff, Lillian B. O'Farrell, Irving F. Moulton, Arthur E. Vollmer, Charles E. Swezy, Alfred Taylor, A.O. White, W.C. Lawrence, C.H. Huntington, F.G. Hail, A.A. Hall, George Louis Tanner. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gregory Family v. City of Elke, Nevada and P.I. Co., ”. Dispute over land., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - “Tax Data Returns - Federal ”., 1933-54 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - “Tax Data Rerurns - Federal 1955 -” to, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - “Tax Data Returns - California, - 1939”. Begins, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - “Tax Data Returns - California, 1940 -” to, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - “Taxes - San Francisco”. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - “Financial Summaries - Louisiana”., July 1927, April 1949, 1956-1964. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - “Louisiana Parish Taxes”., 1933 - 1953. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - “Louisiana State Taxes”. Forms and correspondence, 1944 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - “Louisiana Lands - Oil Lease Revenue, Conoco, ”. Continental Oil Co. Division of interest check stubs., 1955-1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- P.I. Co. - Louisiana
  - “Louisiana - 1909”. List of all P.I. Co. owned land in Louisiana - 27,000 acres in (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Contract of P.I. Co. sale to others, correspondence, agreement with law firm Cline & Plauchï¿½ to represent P.I. Co. interets in Louisiana, map of Evangeline Parish., 1919-1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - “Louisiana Lands 1930-1939”. ( Tax Bill), tax bill displays a bit of political graft, parish assessor asks for campaign contribution in exchange for lowering taxes. Predominantly correspondence re: taxes, sales and rental of land or mineral rights. Copies of abstracts and agreements. Most business handled through Charles Cline - P.I. Co. signs over formal “Power of Attorney” to him., 11/30/31 11/30/31 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Copies of Oil, Cas & Mineral leases, resolutions and routine correspondence Cline and P.I. Co. (Morse or Beaumont)., 1940-1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - “Louisiana Land ”. Oil, Gas and Mineral lease to A.B. Hoose., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Map of Evangeline Parish, Proposed Tate Sand units, Graben Area Reddell Field, Evangeline Parish - maps; routine correspondence. Most of this correspondence is duplicated in JL 10, Box 3. Listing of that gives more complete explanation of contents. There are considerably more legal instruments here., 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - “Louisiana Lands 1951”. Plauchï¿½ & Plauchï¿½ (Cline's former partner) assumed representation of P.I. Co. interests in La. (cf. Box 3, routine correspondence - oil companies request permission to run tests on land in search of oil, 1 ases (surface and mineral) drawn up, State Govt. secures Right of Way Easement Deeds to build highways., JL 10) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Correspondence, Plauchï¿½ - Morse., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Routine correspondence., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Routine correspondence re: taxes and leases, survey map of very small section of land P.I. Co. is leading to a certain Joseph Saucier., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Routine correspondence., 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Includes maps and specifications of P.I. Co. land in Evangeline Parish., 1957 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Detailed maps of tracts of land in Evangeline Parish., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Maps, routine correspondence and memoranda., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Legal instruments, routine correspondence., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - “Louisiana Lands 1965”. Report of revenue and expenses on Louisiana land Routine correspondence, more concerted effort to sell off land., 1955-64. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Correspondence, land sales., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - “Louisiana Lands ”. Final windup of all Louisiana holdings, Quitclaim Deeds, etc., 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - “Small Maps”. Mostly of Evangeline Parish land, some of Acadia Parish. Schedule of land owned by P.I. Co. in Evangeline Parish. Made in total coverage: approx., 1935, 2400 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - “Large Maps”. Of Evangeline and Acadia Parish land, huge map of Southern Louisiana made in shows waterways, oil fields, train tracks., 1934 - (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - “Highway Project Maps”. (Box 5, Folder 26)
- P.I. Co. Land
  - “California Land - General”. Record of Townsite agreements late early other records and reports, earliest date of 15 different contracts made between E.B. Ryan of S.F. and P.I. Co. whereby Ryan buys different parcels of land from P.I. Co. with P.I. Co. land in order to protect it for P.I. Co., 1917, 1918, date - Sept. 1, 1906 - (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - “Index to Maps”. Small notebook. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “Real Property Holdings ”. Listing and description., 1915 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - “Land sale summary ”., 10/15/17 to 12/11/28 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - “Syndicate Lands - Siskiyou, Colusa, Glenn, Tehama and Madera, Sale 1903”. Land put in trust by P.I. Co. and heirs of Big Four, A.D. Shepard as trustee Correspondence and legal instruments re: land to, 1/2/03. dated 1903 July 1906. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Prudential Land Co. - Tehama County ”., 1915-1918 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - “Colusa City - SW 1/4 of S34, T17, R3W”. Certificate of Search and Filling of Deed and Examination of Title to land in Colusa City - particularly described as “the southwest quarter of section 34 in township 17 north, range three (3) west, 1901. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - “Conveyances, Abstracts - Fresno City”. Bound book of memoranda of deeds recorded in the office of the county recorder of Fresno County. Executed by P.I. Co.. Deeds date back to August McKinley Commerative Postcards sent to P.I. Co., 6/4/1906. 1883; 1906 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - “Conveyances by: Contract & Finance Co., Chas. Crocker, P.I. Co. - Humboldt County, Nev.”. Deeds of Conveyance for Humboldt County land, abstract of all lands granted by P.I. Co. between years abstract of conveyances on record in County Recorder's Office of Humboldt County, Nev. from P.I. Co. since, dated: 12/4/1872 - 5/24/1888; 1895 and 1900; 1/1/1900 (- Dec. 1905). (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - “Conveyances - Kern City”. Book #1 P.I. Co. Deeds, Kern County, California not in chronological nor Deed # order, dates of deeds range Book #2 P.I. Co. Deeds Kern County, Calif. no order - All books of conveyances of deeds compiled by Kern County Abstract Co. - Bakersflied, Calif., 1891-1906. dates range 1889-1906. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - “Conveyances - Kern County”. Book #3 P.I. Co. Deeds, Kern County, Ca. Book #4 P.I. Co. Deeds, Kern County, Ca., dates 1889-1906. dates range 1887-1892. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - “Conveyances - Kern County”. Books #5 & #6 same title and subject All books have notations on cover as to what townships in Kern County are included., dates 1887-1905. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - “Abstracts, Conveyances - Merced County”. Notebooks entitled: Abstract of Title. One prepared for P.I. Co. another for Charles Crocker Both prepared by Simonson and Harrell, Merced, Ca. Then two lists: 1. Contract & Finance Co. Deeds, 2. Lots in City of Merced, owned by P.I. Co. -, (dates 1889-1895) (dates 1875-1887). no dates. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - “Placer County E1/2 S13, T14, R16E”. Abstract of Title to 320 acres of land as specified in folder title (ie. eastern 1/2 of section 13, town 14, range 16 east). Property of P.I. Co., 12/16/1921. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - “Siskiyou County S19, T39, R4W”. Abstract of Title for all of section 19 etc., 7/1/20. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - “Tulare County - Portions of S27, T17, R25E, Conveyances”. Conveyances of Deeds Certificate of Title (search), date range 1885-1903. dated 5/13/19. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “P.I. Co. Conveyances - Ventura County”. Bound books containing abstract of deeds (P.I.Co. Conveyances) prepared by Ventura Abstract Co. Booklet subdivided: 1. Schedule A: real property in Saticoy, Ventura County, 2. Schedule B: real property elsewhere (not in Saticoy) in the County of Ventura, dated August 11, 1906. (Box 6, Folder 17)